A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1979-1980
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Administrative Committees
  - Scholarships, Grants-in-Aid, Employment and Loans 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Security and General Safety--Disposal of Ether--Subcommittee--Laser Safety Disposal Hazardous Materials (Empty) 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Student Activities 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Student Health 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Student Rights and Responsibilities (Empty) 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Summer Grants 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Summer Sessions 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Teacher Education 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Traffic Appeals 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Traffic and Parking 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Truman Scholarships 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - University Committee on Students 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - University Press 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - University Union 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1979-1980 (Box 23)
  - Virginia Status of University Students 1979-1980 (Box 23)
- Series III: Permanent Files
  - Air Safety (Administrative Air Travel)--Appointment of Air Safety Officer, Travel of Athletic Teams, Hire of Private Aircraft 1969Oct-1974May (Box 23)
  - Administrative Air Travel 1972Jan-1974Jun (Box 23)
  - Athletics--Randle 1973Dec-1976Mar (Box 23)
  - Awards, Honors, Prizes 1968 Aug-Sep (Box 23)
  - Biology--Personnel 1973May-1976Jan (Box 24)
  - Biology--Seward Forest (1 of 2) 1971 Apr-June (Box 24)
  - Biology--Seward Forest--Proposed Sale of Transfer, Conveyed to County of Brunswick (2 of 2) 1971Aug-1975Apr (Box 24)
  - Birdwood--Residential Colleges, Part II--Costs of Transportation System, Student Poll, Concern of the Community and Builders, Student Council View, Selection of Architect (1 of 2) 1975Jul-1980Jan (Box 24)
  - Birdwood--Residential Colleges, Part II--Albemarle County Views (2 of 2) 1980Feb-1981Jun (Box 24)
  - Birdwood--Residential College--Proposal and Reactions, Report of Student Committee (1 of 3) 1968-1978Aug (Box 24)
  - Birdwood--Residential College (2 of 3) 1978 Aug-Dec (Box 24)
  - Birdwood--Residential College--Environmental Impact (3 of 3) 1979 Jan-Dec (Box 24)
  - Birdwood--Birdwood Building Committee [1968]1979-1980 (Box 24)
  - Blue Ridge Medical Center Transfer Report 1977 Dec (Box 25)
  - Centers, University of Virginia 1969 Mar (Box 25)
  - Christian, Aya--Gift of Furnishings and Art Objects 1968Dec-1978Jul (Box 25)
  - Dabney, Virginius, Part I--History of the University of Virginia:1919-1969, Draft of First Chapter (1 of 4) 1976Nov-1979Jan (Box 25)
  - Dabney, Virginius, Part I--Drafts of Chapters 2 and 3 (2 of 4) 1979 Mar-Jun (Box 25)
  - Dabney, Virginius, Part I--Drafts of Chapters 4 and 5 (3 of 4) 1979 Jul-Sep (Box 25)
  - Dabney, Virginius, Part I--Drafts of Chapters 6 and 7, Comments by President Hereford (4 of 4) 1979 Oct-Dec (Box 25)
  - Demonstrations--Statement by President Shannon (1 of 3) 1968Feb-1969 (Box 25)
  - Demonstrations--Letter from Wm. A. Wright Recommending Action to be Taken, Injunction Against Students Occupying Maury Hall and Reports of Subsequent Action (2 of 3) 1969Jul-1970Jul (Box 25)
  - Demonstrations--Alert and Operations Plan, Clarification of University Regulations, Anti-War Protests (3 of 3) 1970Aug-1975Feb (Box 26)
  - Drugs--Report on Use, Policy Statement 1967Dec-1977Mar (Box 26)
  - Duren Report--Lowering of Faculty Retirement Age 1975Apr-1976Apr (Box 26)
  - Duren Report--Ad Hoc--Faculty Staffing and Planning, 1973-1974 1973Jun-1975Dec (Box 26)
  - Emergency Plan--To Cope with Potential Disorders, Reports and Analyses of Several Incidents 1970Aug-1974Feb (Box 26)
  - Federal Executive Institute--Prospectus for Lease; Testimony Before Committee on Public Works, U.S. Senate Bill; Bill to Authorize Bonds; Executive Staff College (1 of 3) 1973Jul-Oct (Box 26)
  - Federal Executive Institute--Proposal for Establishment, Action by President Nixon, Action by General Assembly (2 of 3) 1974Apr-1975Mar (Box 26)
  - Federal Executive Institute--Reduced Scope of Project, Request for Information by William Preston (3 of 3) 1975Apr-1980Apr (Box 26)
  - Garden Club of Virginia--Restoration of the Gardens, East Lawn (1 of 3) 1948Jan-1961May (Box 27)
  - Garden Club of Virginia (2 of 3) 1961Jul-1963Feb (Box 27)
  - Garden Club of Virginia (3 of 3) 1963Apr-1975Dec (Box 27)
  - Gay Student Union--Dispute Concerning Allocation by Student Council (1 of 3) 1972Dec-1973Jan (Box 27)
  - Gay Student Union--Denied by Board of Visitors, Transcript of Committee Hearing (2 of 3) 1973 Jan-Mar (Box 27)
  - Gay Student Union--Report of Student Affairs Committee of Board of Visitors, Gay Hotline (3 of 3) 1975 Nov-Dec (Box 27)
  - Governor's Executive Orders--Travel Regulations, Authority of Secretaries (1 of 2) 1972Jun-1976Jul (Box 27)
  - Governor's Executive Orders--Affirmative Action Plan (2 of 2) 1976Aug-1977Dec (Box 27)
  - Governor Godwin's Emergency Executive Orders 1977 Jan-Feb (Box 27)
  - Governor Godwin's Office Response to HEW--Appendices, A-H (1 of 2) No Date (Box 27)
  - Governor Godwin's Office Response to HEW--Plan for Equal Opportunity (Reformulation), HEW Initial Analysis, Commonwealth Response (2 of 2) 1977 Sep-Dec (Box 28)
  - Gwathmey Award 1963Nov-1974Apr (Box 28)
  - Health, Education and Welfare--Desegregation Plan (HEW) (1 of 3) 1977Jul-1978Apr (Box 28)
  - Health, Education and Welfare--Equal Opportunity Employment Plan, Complaints by Women's Alliance (HEW) (2 of 3) 1978 May-Jun (Box 28)
  - Health, Education and Welfare--Revised Plan for Equal Opportunity Employment, Plan for Student Recruitment, Race Discrimination Complaint by K. Easley (HEW) (3 of 3) 1978Jul-1979Sep (Box 28)
  - HEW On-Site Review--Complaint Investigations and Contract Compliance Review, Acceptance of Affirmative Action Plan 1978 Apr-Jul (Box 28)
  - HEW Clippings 1978 Mar-Apr (Box 28)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation--Joint Committee on Founder's Day 1976Mar-1977Feb (Box 28)
  - Jefferson Park Avenue Property 1975Aug-1978Aug (Box 28)
  - Kuper, Theodore Fred--Thomas Jefferson and Slavery, Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation, Memoirs of Claude Bowers (1 of 2) 1932Mar-1972Sep (Box 28)
  - Kuper, Theodore Fred--Tribute to Gilbert Chinard, George Washington Foundation for Citizenship (2 of 2) 1972Nov-1978Jan (Box 28)
  - Lambeth Field Access Road 1973Aug-1976Oct (Box 29)
  - Law School Phase II 1975May-1980Mar (Box 29)
  - Law School Deanship 1975Oct-1979Apr (Box 29)
  - Lawn Society--Meeting 1979 Oct (Box 29)
  - Legal Advisor Time Report--E.A.I.R.I. 1981 Jan-Jun (Box 29)
  - Legal Advisor Time Reports--S.U.P. 1978Aug-1980Dec (Box 29)
  - Medical Center--Blue Ridge Hospital--Plan for Building New Hospital, Removal of the Medical Center (1 of 5) 1980 May-Sep (Box 29)
  - Medical Center--Blue Ridge Hospital--Objections by Medical Faculty ( 2 of 5) 1980 Sep (Box 29)
  - Medical Center--Blue Ridge Hospital--Reactions to the Proposal (3 of 5) 1980 Sep-Dec (Box 29)
  - Medical Center--Blue Ridge Hospital--Reactions (4 of 5) 1981 Jan (Box 29)
  - Medical Center--Blue Ridge Hospital--Reactions (5 of 5) 1981 Feb-Mar (Box 29)
  - Medical School--East Wing--Medical Center Expansion, Debt Capacity Study 1977Aug-1979Jun (Box 30)
  - Planning for 1975-1980 and 1976-1982 1975Dec-1979Feb (Box 30)
  - Planning--Albemarle County 1972Feb-1976Feb (Box 30)
  - Planning--Medical Center--Cobb Building Elevator Addition 1977Feb-1979May (Box 30)
  - Planning--Medical Center--Primary Care Center Parking Lot 1978 Apr-Oct (Box 30)
  - Planning--Medical Center--Renal Dialysis 1976 Mar-Apr (Box 30)
  - Planning--Medical Center--12th Street, 2 Lots Medical Center 1976Jan-1980Feb (Box 30)
  - Planning and Budget--6 year Expenditure Plan 1976 Sep (Box 30)
  - Scott Stadium--General, Part I--Expansion Project; Structural Problems, Settlement 1978Jul-1981Feb (Box 30)
  - Scott Stadium--Gifts and Pledges, Thank-You's 1976Aug-1981Oct (Box 30)
  - Scott Stadium--Scott Family 1974Mar-1977Feb (Box 30)
  - Scott Stadium Addition--Special Committee (1 of 3) 1973Mar-1975Aug (Box 30)
  - Scott Stadium Addition--Special Committee (2 of 3) 1975Nov-1977Dec (Box 31)
  - Scott Stadium Addition--Special Committee (3 of 3) 1978 Jan-Jun (Box 31)
  - Scott Stadium--Frantzreb and Pray Associates Study 1974May-1975Jan (Box 31)
  - Scott Stadium--Feb. 22, 1975 Meeting 1975 Feb (Box 31)
  - Scott Stadium--Williams and Tazewell and Associates 1973Feb-1974Jul (Box 31)
  - Shaner Report--Text of Management Consultants' Report (1 of 2) No Date (Box 31)
  - Shaner Report--Reactions to the Report (2 of 2) 1973Sep-1978Aug (Box 31)
  - Student Affairs--Assault and Rape 1975Feb-1977Jan (Box 31)
  - Student Housing--Catlin's File 1975Nov-1977Jul (Box 31)
  - University Houses, "Morea"-"Hotel D"--Inventory of Furnishings, Occupancy Assignments (1 of 2) 1971Apr-1973Sep (Box 31)
  - University Houses, "Morea"-"Hotel D" (2 of 2) 1974Jan-1981Aug (Box 31)
  - Vice President Prospects 1973Sep-1975Jan (Box 31)
  - Word Processing--Equipment Options, Proposal (1 of 2) 1978 May (Box 32)
  - Word Processing--State Directive, Work Study (2 of 2) 1978Jun-1980Apr (Box 32)
  - Younger, Edward E.--History of Virginia Since 1865 1967Oct-1979Apr (Box 32)
  - Special Committee--Animal Care Facilities 1976May-1980Apr (Box 32)
  - Special Committee--Birdwood Building--Student Council Plan 1978Sep-1980Apr (Box 32)
  - Special Committee--Carruthers Hall Building 1979Oct-1981Feb (Box 32)
  - Special Committee--Commission to Study Fraternities and Sororities (1 of 2) 1979Apr-1980Apr (Box 32)
  - Special Committee--Commission to Study Fraternities and Sororities--Report, Reactions (2 of 2) 1980May-1981Dec (Box 32)
  - Special Committee--Graduate Tuition and Fee 1980 Mar-Apr (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Lambeth Colonnades 1976Jan-1978Nov (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Medical Center Parking Garage 1974Apr-1981Jul (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Peabody/Newcomb Space Allocation 1978May-1980Oct (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Physics Building Addition 1978Nov-1980Jan (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Psychology, Psychiatry, Psychiatric Nursing 1977Mar-1978Sep (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Resource Recovery Study Commission--Solid: Solid Wastes as Fuel 1975Jan-1981Mar (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Self-Study Handicapped 1977Dec-1978Jul (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Building Committee Sponsors Hall--Executive Programs Center 1975Sep-1980Jun (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Student Recreation Building 1975Jul-1979Nov (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Telecommunications Council (1 of 2) 1973Jan-1977Jun (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Telecommunications Council (2 of 2) 1977Jul-1980Jun (Box 33)
  - Special Committee--Undergraduate Library 1976Aug-1982Mar (Box 34)
- Series IV: Ad Hoc Committees
  - Search Committee for Dean of Architecture--Appointment of Jaquelin Taylor Robertson 1979Jan-1980Jun (Box 34)
  - Athletic Program Director Search 1970Sep-1980Nov (Box 34)
  - Athletic Program Director Search--Appointment of Richard D. Schultz 1980Dec-1981Feb (Box 34)
  - Carruthers Hall 1979Aug-1981Dec (Box 34)
  - Employee I.D. Cards 1979Jul-1980Oct (Box 34)
  - Search for Dean of Faculty of Arts and Sciences--Appointment of Merrill D. Peterson 1980Sep-1981Mar (Box 34)
  - Faculty Handbook 1969Sep-1974Sep (Box 34)
  - Feasibility Study--Computers for Planning 1980 Aug (Box 34)
  - Fire Safety--Medical Center 1976May-1977Nov (Box 34)
  - Form Review Committee 1977Mar-1978Jul (Box 34)
  - Law School Dean Search Committee--Appointment of Richard A. Merrill 1979 Apr-Oct (Box 34)
  - Lawn Lighting 1975Nov-1976Apr (Box 34)
  - Provost Search Committee--Appointment of Edwin Floyd 1980Apr-1981Jun (Box 35)
  - Science and Engineering Research Building 1979Apr-1980Mar (Box 35)
  - University Water Conservation 1981 Feb (Box 35)
- Series V: Restricted Material
  - Ad Hoc--Medical Center Administrative Structure--Vice President for Health Services (1 of 4) 1971Jan-1976Mar (Box 36)
  - Ad Hoc--Medical Center Administrative Structure--Appointment of a Special Committee (2 of 4) 1976 Jan-May (Box 36)
  - Ad Hoc--Medical Center Administrative Structure--First Committee Meeting (3 of 4) 1976 Jun (Box 36)
  - Ad Hoc--Medical Center Administrative Structure--Appointment of Vice President Harry Muller (4 of 4) 1976 Jul-Sep (Box 36)